Guide to the Culver Family Papers, 1858-1915
Department of Special Collections
- Correspondence & Miscellaneous Papers, Family and Friends, 1850s-1900s; n.d.
  - To Minnie Culver from Isobell Bennett [Mrs. Charles W.], 1860s., (18 letters) (Box 4, Folder 15)
    See also Box 12, F4 for additional letters from Isobel Bennett.
  - To Minnie Culver from Ellen Carpenter [Woodworth], 1860s., (11 letters) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - To/from Minnie Culver from Belle Finlayson, 1860s., (5 letters) (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Civil War: 10th and 17th Reg'ts., Wisconsin Volunteer Infantry. Wartime St. Louis.
  - To/from Minnie & Oscar Culver and John & Jennie Hayner, 1860s., (8 letters) (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Civil War: housing invalid soldiers.
  - To Minnie Culver from Miscellaneous, 1860s., (9 letters) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - From Minnie Culver to Miscellaneous, 1860s., (4 letters) (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Culver Family Bills & Receipts, 1860s., (22 items) (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - To/from James H. Howe & Miscellaneous, 1860s., (7 letters) (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Wisconsin politics. Timothy O. Howe.
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Neither to Nor from Culver Family, 1860s., (4 letters) (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Republican State Convention, Wisconsin 1860. Wisconsin state politics.
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1870s., (10 letters) (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Iron mining [Wisconsin], gold mining [California].
  - To Minnie Culver from Zebina Bliss, 1870s., (5 letters) (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Insurance business.
  - To Minnie Culver from Edwin, Mary S. & Timothy Bliss, 1870s., (3 letters) (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - To Minnie Culver from Julia Bliss, 1870s., (20 letters) (Box 4, Folder 27)
    See also Box 8, F26-33 for undated correspondence from Julia Bliss to Minnie Culver.
  - To Minnie Culver from Nell Bliss, 1870s., (26 letters) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    See also, Box 12 F9 for letter to Minnie Culver from Nell Bliss, Sep [?], 1874.
  - To Minnie Culver from Will Culver, 1870s., (5 letters) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Gold mining and camp life, California. Ranching, So. California.
  - To Minnie Culver from "Mellie," 1870s., (7 letters) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - To Minnie Culver from Culver Relatives, 1870s., (13 letters) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Question of the Bible in schools. [Reuben Eaton] Fenton [U.S. Senator, NY]. Pottery painting and tracing techniques.
  - To Minnie Culver from Miscellaneous, 1870s., (20 letters) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - To Oscar Culver from Minnie Culver, 1870s., (15 letters) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Art lessons, [?] Wyant and [?] Bascom, New York. Iron mining. Opera.
  - To Oscar Culver from His Brothers, 1870s., (9 letters) (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Society wedding, 1870. Iron mining.
  - To Oscar Culver from Bliss Relatives, 1870s., (7 letters) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Country life, Colorado. Cattle and sheep ranching, Colorado and Texas, 1870s.
  - To Oscar Culver from David C. Atwood, 1870s., (5 letters) (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Wisconsin State Journal. David C. Atwood [U.S. Congressman, WI]. Wisconsin Republican politics.
  - To Oscar Culver from Timothy O. Howe & James H. Howe, 1870s., (11 letters) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Wisconsin politics. Carl Schurz. [Henry Bowen] Anthony [U.S. Senator, RI]. The U.S. Senate. Iron mining.
  - To/from Oscar Culver & John J. McClellan, 1870-1873., (16 letters) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Real estate business. Pottery clay. Mining speculation. Iron and silver mining.
  - To/from Oscar Culver & John J. McClellan, 1874-1876., (9 letters) (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Mining.
  - To Oscar Culver as Editor [Wisconsin State Journal], 1870s., (6 letters) (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Wisconsin State Journal. Education. Timothy O. Howe. Wisconsin and national Republican politics. Horace Rublee.
  - To Oscar Culver from Miscellaneous, 1870s., (26 letters) (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Wisconsin Republican politics. Life insurance. Iron mining. Mineral assays. Real estate: sales, leasing, mortgages. Mining exploration and ore milling.
  - From Oscar Culver to Miscellaneous, 1870s., (2 letters) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - To Will Culver from Oscar Culver and Julia Bliss, 1870s., (2 letters) (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Northern California wilderness. Lynching.
  - To Julia Louise Culver from Louise B. Culver, 1870s., (1 letter) (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - To Timothy B. Bliss & Cornelia E. (Nell) Bliss from Julia & Ellen Bliss, 1870s., (2 letters) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - To Emily Drury from Cornelia Bliss, 1870s., (1 letter) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Undetermined Addressee and Writer, 1870., (1 letter) (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Central California wilderness.
  - Culver Bills and Receipts, 1870s., (28 items) (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1880-1882., (21 letters) (Box 5, Folder 22)
    George Bliss Culver. J. H. Howe. Salinas, CA. Train travel, Northern California. Postal Inspector in the field. Virginia City, NV. "Haverlys Celebrated Minstrels." Building material costs, Northern California. National politics.
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1883-1887., (18 letters) (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Postal inspector in the field. Frank Bros. Agricultural Implements Co., San Francisco, CA, & Portland, OR.
  - To Oscar Culver from Minnie Culver, 1880-1882., (19 letters) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Homesteading and farming life, Napa Valley, CA, 1880s.
  - To Oscar Culver from Minnie Culver, 1883-1885., (12 letters) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Farming and social life, Napa Valley, Ca, 1880s.
  - To Oscar Culver from Minnie Culver, 1886-1889., (11 letters) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Farming and social life, Napa Valley, CA, 1880s.
  - To Oscar & Minnie Culver from New York Culver Relatives, 1880s. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Joseph Potter, Justice NY Supreme Court. W. A. Wakeman, [U.S. Congressman]. New York politics & economic conditions, U. S. Grant funeral. Edward F. Burton, Director, U.S. Mint, San Francisco.
  - To Oscar and Minnie Culver from Will Culver, 1881-1883., (13 letters) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Painting techniques. Henry Villard.
  - To Oscar and Minnie Culver from Will and Margaret Culver, 1884-1888., (14 letters) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Prices, San Francisco, 1884.
  - To Minnie Culver from Paul Culver, 1880s., (7 letters) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Portland, OR, 1882.
  - To Minnie & Oscar Culver from Bliss Relatives, 1880s., (13 letters) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - To Minnie Culver from Miscellaneous (non-relatives), 1880s., (18 letters) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - To Oscar Culver from Miscellaneous (non-relatives), 1880-1883., (17 letters) (Box 6, Folder 10)
    James H. Howe. Wisconsin politics. Horace Rublee. Land speculation. See also, Box 13, F4 for letters to Oscar Culver as Post Office Inspector.
  - To Oscar Culver from Miscellaneous (non-relatives), 1885-1888., (11 letters) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    John C[olt] Spooner (U.S. Senator, Wis.). National politics. See also, Box 12, F10 for additional letters to Oscar Culver from misc., & Box 13, F5-7 for letters to Oscar Culver as Post Office Inspector.
  - From Oscar and Minnie Culver to Miscellaneous, 1880s., (3 letters) (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Gold mining.
  - To Will Culver from Minnie, Paul, & Richard Culver, 1880s., (4 letters) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - To Will and Paul Culver from Miscellaneous, 1880s., (2 letters) (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Social life, Napa Valley, CA, 1880s.
  - To Louise [Lulu] Culver from Minnie & Paul Culver, 1880s., (15 letters) (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Social life Napa Valley, CA, 1880s.
  - To Louise Culver from Will Culver, 1880s., (2 letters) (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - To Louise Culver from Culver Cousins, 1880s., (1 letter) (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - To Louise [Lulu] Culver from Miscellaneous, 1880s., (13 letters) (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - To/from Drury-Bliss Relatives, 1880s., (3 letters) (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1880s., (7 letters) (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Receipts & Newsclippings, 1880s., (7 items) (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence and Misc. Papers, Family and Friends, 1890s-1900s. (Box 7)
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1890s., (3 letters) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Prof. Hopkins, St. Helena, CA, Fruit tree expert. Citrus culture.
  - To Oscar Culver from Minnie & Louise Culver, 1890s., (15 letters) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    [no letters 1894-1896] Social life in Napa Valley, 1890s. Palo Alto, CA. 50-sec. Earthquake. SF/Oakland. Professional community, Palo Alto. Steamer trip, Portland-San Francisco.
  - To Oscar Culver from Thomas, Stephen, and George Culver, 1890s., (3 letters) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Loyal Legion [military order]. Family History.
  - To Oscar Culver from Richard and Will Culver, 1890s., (2 letters) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Remenyi [violinist], Musan [or Musin], [violinist].
  - To Oscar and Will Culver from Miscellaneous, 1890s., (7 letters) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    See also, Box 13, F6 for letter to Oscar Culver from F. W. Warner, Mar 8, 1899. Gold mining.
  - To Minnie Culver from Stephen Culver, Louise Culver, & Mary Eliza Richards, 1890s., (3 letters) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - To Minnie Culver from Julia [Bliss] Bayera, 1890s., (1 letter) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    See also, Box 8, F26-33 for undated correspondence from Julia [Bliss] Bayera to Minnie Culver.
  - To Minnie Culver from the Will Culvers, 1890s., (8 letters) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Visit to "Big Trees" [CA]
  - To Minnie Culver from Louise [Lulu] Culver, 1890s., (12 letters) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Campus life [Stanford University]. [David Starr] Jordan. A teacher's life.
  - To Minnie & Oscar Culver from Richard and George Culver, 1890s., (15 letters) (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Smithsonian Institution, Zoological Park. Spanish-American War fever. Political climate, Washington, D.C., late 1980s. Sketches by Richard Culver. Sacramento, CA, characterized.
  - To Minnie Culver from Miscellaneous, 1890s., (12 letters) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Life in London 1890s [with sketches].
  - Sketch by Will Culver, 1892. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - To Will Culver from Oscar and Minnie Culver, George Culver, & Louise Culver, 1890s., (6 letters) (Box 7, Folder 13)
    See also, Box 12, F11 for letter to Will Culver from George Bliss Culver, Apr 28, 1898. Benefits of cooperatives. Monterey, Carmel, CA, 1898. Early arrivals Monterey [Mrs. Allen; Mrs. Walter Little]. John Phoenix, Phoenixiana Magazine. Cattle drive, Carmel [vaqueros and riatas].
  - To Louise [Lulu] Culver from Minnie & Oscar Culver, 1890s., (8 letters) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - To Louise Culver from the Will Culvers, 1890s., (5 letters) (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Jack London. Stanford University.
  - To Louise Culver from George Bliss Culver, 1890s., (1 letter) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - To Louise Culver from Richard K. Culver, 1890s., (2 letters) (Box 7, Folder 17)
    Sketch by Richard Culver.
  - To Louise Culver from Culver Cousins, 1890s., (3 letters) (Box 7, Folder 18)
    Wally Foote [U.S. Congressman, NY]. [?] Benedict, Curator, Smithsonian. Dr. [?] Featherstonhaugh. RMS Majestic. A visit to France & Spain, 1893.
  - To Louise Culver from Miscellaneous, 1890s., (11 letters) (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - To George Bliss Culver from Family & Friends, 1890s., (12 letters, 3 are duplicates) (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - To Richard Culver from George Culver, 1890s., (3 letters) (Box 7, Folder 21)
    See also, Box 12, F11 for letter to Richard Culver from George B. Culver, Apr 25, 1898.
  - To Culver Children from Minnie Culver on the death of a foster child, 1894., (1 letter) (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - To Mary Eliza [Culver] Richards from Frederick Richards, 1890s., (3 letters) (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Europe, 1893. See also, Box 7, F18 for letter to "Dear Coz" from Fred [Richards], Feb 12, 1893.
  - To/from Thomas L. Culver & Miscellaneous, 1890s., (3 letters) (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - To Miscellaneous from Drury Relatives, 1890s., (2 letters) (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous Non-Culver Correspondence, 1890s., (4 letters) (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Receipts & Announcements, 1890s., (8 items) (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - To Oscar Culver from Will Culver, 1900s., (2 letters) (Box 7, Folder 28)
    Book of Job.
  - To Oscar Culver from Friends, 1900s., (1 letter) (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1900s., (1 letter) (Box 7, Folder 30)
    Ben Lomond [CA].
  - To Minnie & Oscar Culver from George B[radley] Culver, 1900s., (2 letters) (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - To Minnie & Oscar from George Bliss Culver, 1900s., (11 letters) (Box 7, Folder 32)
    Pacific coast mining. Law school.
  - To Minnie, Oscar, Louise, & Doris Culver from Richard Culver, 1900s., (6 letters) (Box 7, Folder 33)
    See also, Box 12, F12 for letter to Oscar Culver from Richard Culver, Mar 29, 1901.
  - To Minnie & Doris Culver from Will Culver, 1900s., (17 letters) (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - To Minnie Culver from Louise & Nina Culver, 1900s., (3 letters) (Box 7, Folder 35)
    Geneology of Bliss-Drury-Hapgood families.
  - To Minnie Culver from M. Eliza [Culver] Richards, 1900s., (1 letter) (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - To Minnie Culver from Julia [Bliss] Bayera, 1900s., (3 letters) (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - To Minnie Culver from Martha [Bliss] & Kate Chipman, 1900s., (5 letters) (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - To Minnie Culver from Miscellaneous, 1900s., (17 letters) (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - To Will Culver from Oscar & Minnie Culver, 1900s., (3 letters) (Box 7, Folder 40)
    Bliss geneology.
  - To Will Culver from Paul & Nina, George, & Richard Culver, 1900s., (13 letters) (Box 7, Folder 41)
    Black Bear mine [CA]. Newspapers & artists.
  - To Will Culver from Eastern Culver Relatives, 1900s., (2 letters) (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Bandits North River, NY. Culver children.
  - To Will Culver from Miscellaneous, 1900s., (3 letters) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Fruit farming [Lindsay, CA]. Mining.
  - To Louise Culver from Minnie Culver, 1900s., (6 letters) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - To Louise Culver from Will Culver, 1900s., (15 letters) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Camp Reverie Assoc., Forestville, CA [camping]. Land dealings. Rail travel and pulmonary consumption.
  - To Louise Culver from George Bliss Culver, 1900s., (5 letters) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Washington, D.C. July 4th at Great Falls Park, VA.
  - To Louise Culver from Richard K. Culver, 1900s., (10 letters) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Los Angeles, Baltimore. Cartoon art.
  - To Louise Culver from Nina & Sabina Culver, 1900s., (4 letters) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - To Louise Culver from Thomas L. and Charles M. Culver, 1900s., (3 letters) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - To Louise Culver from Miscellaneous, 1900s., (16 letters) (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Mrs. Kate Gilman [Gilman St., Palo Alto], Rev. F. J. Culver. Mrs. Leland Stanford. Marion Dole Jones.
  - To George Bliss Culver from Minnie Culver, 1900s., (1 letter) (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - To George Bliss Culver from Laura Culver & Thomas L. Culver, 1900s., (2 letters) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - To George Bliss Culver from Miscellaneous 1900s., (1 letter) (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1900s., (10 letters) (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Receipts, Cash Acct., Receipt for Stock Shares, 1900s., (6 items) (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Pamphlets & Clippings, 1900s., (5 documents) (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - To Oscar Culver from Minnie Culver, Undated [1860s-1870s?]., (4 letters, 3 notes) (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - To Oscar Culver from Minnie Culver, Undated [1880s-1890s?]., (18 letters) (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - To Oscar Culver from Julia Bliss, Undated., (2 letters) (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - To Oscar Culver from Thomas Culver, Undated., (3 partial letters) (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - To Oscar Culver from Miscellaneous, Undated., (9 items) (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - To Oscar Culver from George Gibson, Undated., (2 letters) (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, Undated., (4 letters) (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - To Minnie Culver from Will Culver, Undated., (1 letter) (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - To Minnie & Louise Culver from Paul & Nina Culver, Undated., (3 letters) (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - To Minnie Culver from Julia Louise Culver, Undated., (10 letters) (Box 8, Folder 25)
    Teacher's life, Napa Valley, CA.
  - To Minnie Culver & Zebina Bliss from Julia Bliss from Vermont & Illinois, Undated [pre- 1872]., (3 letters) (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - To Minnie Culver from Julia Bliss from Quebec, Undated., (3 letters) (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - To Minnie Culver from Julia Bliss from Wisconsin, Undated., (3 letters) (Box 8, Folder 28)
    See also, Box 12, F4 for undated letter from Brown's Lake [WI], "Sunday Morning".
  - To Minnie & Nellie Bliss from Julia Bliss from Colorado, Undated [1870s?]., (11 letters) (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - To Minnie Culver from Julia [Bliss] Bayera from Ocean View [San Francisco], Undated., (8 letters) (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - To Minnie Culver from Julia [Bliss] Bayera from Oakland & Novato, CA, Undated., (5 letters) (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - To Minnie Culver from Julia Bliss [Bayera], Undated & No Point of Origin., (7 complete letters and 6 partial) (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Correspondence and Photographs, Family and Friends (Undated), and Family Journals, 1860-1893
  - To Minnie Culver from Nellie Bliss, Undated., (3 letters) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - To Minnie and Louise Culver from Linda and Mary [Bayera], Undated., (4 letters) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - To Minnie Culver from Jennie [Drury] Hayner, Undated., (3 letters) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Reports of danger to travelers from Indians, St. Louis to Fort Benton, MO [1863?].
  - To Minnie Culver & Julia Bliss from Sara Saxe, Undated., (2 letters) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - To Minnie Culver from New York Culver Relatives, Undated., (5 letters) (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Artist [?] [?] Wyant, NY.
  - To Minnie Culver from Miscellaneous, Undated., (18 letters) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - To Will Culver from Miscellaneous, Undated., (1 letter) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - To Will & Paul Culver from Minnie, Oscar, & Louise Culver, Undated., (4 letters) (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Modoc mine. Value of sulphurets in mine tailings.
  - To/from Margaret Culver and Minnie Culver, Undated., (2 letters) (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - To Louise {Lulu] Culver from Minnie Culver & Julia Bliss, Undated., (9 letters & 4 partial) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - To Louise Culver from Miscellaneous, Undated., (4 letters & 3 partial) (Box 9, Folder 11)
    David Starr Jordan. See also, Box 12, F15 for additional letter "Dear Louise," signed "NBC" [Nina B. Culver].
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated & Unattributed., (8 letters, some partial) (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Culver Family Photographs, Unlabeled & Undated., (8 photographs) (Box 9, Folder 13)
    [Five, 3" x 3", family groupings (outdoors); one, 2" x 2", family grouping (outdoors); one, 3" x 3", milling machinery; one, ~1", oval cameo of unknown man]. See also Box 11, F5 for two additional photographs.
  - Journal, Unknown Writer, No Date [1860s?]., (1 page) (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Journal (partial) Minnie B. Culver, 1863)., (42 pages) (Box 9, Folder 15)
    St. Louis: Civil War rallies & illuminations, rumors of Confederate perfidy, city on alert, charity benefits for soldiers, Union League, transport of Indians, Murdock lecture on "National Destiny." Sleighing, St. Louis theater, Matilda Heron in Bell of the Season, [Louis] Gottschalk and [Adelina] Patti, Phoenix, magazine. Halleck Guards, 96th Reg't. Illinois Volunteer Infantry, 3rd Wisconsin Battery [Artillery], 1st Wisconsin Cavalry, MGen. Samuel R. Curtis, MGen. John McNeil vs Gen. John S. Marmaduke (C.S.A.), casualty lists. U.S.S. Newsboy. Steamers Planet & Florence. Alton, IL, Cape Girardeau, MO.
  - Pocket Journal, J. Oscar Culver as Postal Inspector, 1886., (251 pages) (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Pocket Record Book, J. Oscar Culver [1888?]notes on tax assessment records., (108 pages) (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Pocket Journal, Louise Culver [1889?]., (81 pages) (Box 9, Folder 18)
    Napa Valley, CA.
  - Pocket Journal, J. Oscar Culver as Postal Inspector, 1890., (62 pages) (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Pocket Journal, J. Oscar Culver as Postal Inspector [1891?]., (89 pages) (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Pocket Journal, J. Oscar Culver as Postal Inspector & Miscellaneous, 1893., (62 pages) (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Journal (portion) Minnie Culver, [1893?]., (5 pages) (Box 9, Folder 22)
    Monterey Peninsula, CA.
  - Pocket Journal (portion) Louise Culver [1893?]., (1 pages) (Box 9, Folder 23)
    Pacific Grove, CA.
- Family Journals and Record Books, 1895-1908.
  - Pocket Journal (portion), Louise Culver, 1895., (2 pages, 2 x 5") (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Campus life, Stanford University.
  - Pocket Handbook, California Legislature, 1897[Richard Keith Culver]., (128 pages + 8 pages of notes by R. K. Culver). 10 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    3 Pocket Journal, Louise Culver, 1901. (80 pages of notes) Los Angeles. Palo Alto. Teaching.
  - Pocket Record Book, J. Oscar Culver as Postal Inspector, 1901., (77 pages of notes) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Pocket Journal, Louise Culver, 1902., (176 pages of notes) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Palo Alto, CA.
  - Pocket Record Book, J. Oscar Culver as Postal Inspector, 1902., (77 pages of notes) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Pocket Journal, Louise Culver, 1906., (295 pages of notes) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Pocket Journal, Louise Culver, 1908., (72 pages of notes) (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Pocket Journal, Louise Culver, 1909., (369 pages of notes) (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Family Journals, 1910-1915; Cookbook, Undated.
  - Pocket Journal, Louise Culver, 1910., (101 pages of notes) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Pocket Journal, Louise Culver, 1913., (365 pages of notes) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Pocket Journal, Louise Culver, 1914., (365 pages of notes) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Pocket Journal, Louise Culver, 1915., (367 pages of notes) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The Everyday Cookbook. No Date., (315 pages with index) (Box 11, Folder 5)
    [Cameo photographs of two women glued to first page.]
- Correspondence and Literary Drafts, 1859-1900s.
  - J. O. Culver Geneology., (1 document) (Oversize 12, Folder 1)
    Relates J. O. Culver lineage to Revolutionary War.
  - To Minnie Culver from Oscar Culver, 1860s., (6 letters) (Oversize 12, Folder 2)
    Hazards to Paymasters in the field, 1860s. Paymaster's life day by day.
  - To Minnie & Oscar Culver from Miscellaneous Relatives, 1860s., (2 letters) (Oversize 12, Folder 3)
  - To Oscar & Minnie from Charles & Isobell Bennett, 1859-1860s., (11 letters) (Oversize 12, Folder 4)
    Legal business in Wisconsin 1859-1860s. School board conflicts, Wis. 1860s.
  - To Minnie Culver from Mary E. [Drury] Westover [aka Luella], 1859-1860s., (14 letters) (Oversize 12, Folder 5)
    Burlington and Summit, Wis., social life, 1860s.
  - To Oscar & Minnie Culver from George (& Mary D.) Westover, 1859-1860., (16 letters) (Oversize 12, Folder 6)
    Law business. Music. Family relations.
  - To Oscar & Minnie Culver from George (& Mary D.) Westover, 1861-1866., (18 letters) (Oversize 12, Folder 7)
    Vicksburg. Union soldiers object to orders by commanders. Pay Dept. Family relations. Effects of the Civil War.
  - To Oscar & Minnie Culver from Miscellaneous, 1850s& 1860s., (6 letters) (Oversize 12, Folder 8)
  - To Oscar & Minnie Culver from Miscellaneous, 1870s., (2 letters) (Oversize 12, Folder 9)
  - To Oscar & Minnie Culver from Miscellaneous, 1880s., (3 letters) (Oversize 12, Folder 10)
  - To Will & Richard Culver from George Bliss Culver, 1890s., (2 letters) (Oversize 12, Folder 11)
  - To Oscar Culver from Richard Keith Culver, 1900s., (1 letter) (Oversize 12, Folder 12)
  - To Louise Culver from Will Culver, 1900s., (1 letter) (Oversize 12, Folder 13)
  - To Minnie Culver from Nellie & Julia [Bliss], Undated., (3 letters) (Oversize 12, Folder 14)
  - To Louise Culver from Nina B. Culver, Undated., (1 letter) (Oversize 12, Folder 15)
  - Oscar Culver, Fiction Drafts, I, Undated., (7 documents, 41 pages) (Oversize 12, Folder 16)
  - Oscar Culver, Fiction Drafts, II, Undated., (3 documents, 37 pages) (Oversize 12, Folder 17)